#### Contact

www.linkedin.com/in/sanketatal (LinkedIn)

### Top Skills

Software Development
Databases
Oracle

## Languages

English

#### **Patents**

Processing records from a database Applying distinct Hash-Join distributions of operators to both even and uneven database records

# Sanket Atal

Managing Director at Intuit Bengaluru

## Summary

26+ years of experience in Software Development with Enterprise Software (Informix, Oracle and CA Tech) and E-Commerce (MakeMyTrip) companies, working in the US and India with geographically distributed teams. Execution focused with experience in business strategy, innovation, enterprise architecture, research & development, engineering, operations, program management, and process/governance.

BS in CS & Mathematics, MS in CS, MBA.

## Experience

Intuit India
Managing Director
May 2018 - Present (2 years 4 months)
Bangalore, India

# Oracle

Group Vice President October 2014 - April 2018 (3 years 7 months) Bangalore

MakeMyTrip.com Chief Technical Officer June 2012 - August 2014 (2 years 3 months) Gurgaon, Haryana, India

Responsible for all technology including hosting infrastructure and all software development for India's largest Online Travel Agency (USD 1.25+ billion gross bookings). Helped acquire and integrate companies in Thailand, Singapore, Netherlands and Israel. Completely revamped the development process with Agile methodologies, introduced accountability with project ROI tracking and transparency using Dashboards and metrics. Redesigned all UI to be responsive and function on all form-factors, and built in-house teams to create

native applications on Android and iOS. Created a BI solution to leverage Big Data and power business decisions and personalization. Created automation solutions to improve operational excellence in call centers.

### CA Technologies

SVP and GM, India Technology Center June 2010 - June 2012 (2 years 1 month)

Ran the Hyderabad R&D center. Shepherded the growth of the center with a third of all software development being done in Hyderabad and significant products completely produced there. It became the largest R&D center for CA world-wide with 2500+ people. Worked very closely with business to better serve the region.

#### **Oracle Corporation**

Vice President, R&D, India Development Center January 1996 - June 2010 (14 years 6 months) Portland, OR, USA and Bangalore, India

Worked at various levels during my tenure.

Headed the Server Technology Organization (DBMS, Middleware, Systems Management) in India with responsibility for people across India. Worked extensively with US Mgmt on developing and implementing organization wide strategic initiatives.

Portland, Oregon, USA (01/1997 – 07/2006)

- \* Co-founder of the Portland Development Center (PDC). Grew the office from 12 to 120 employees.
- \* Managed three software development teams. Two in Portland, Oregon and one in Bangalore. The teams work towards the foundational high-availability infrastructure as well as the Oracle HTTP Server (Web-server).
- \* Coordinated development across 15+ teams located in various parts of the world including, Bangalore, Sydney, Nashua, Redwood City, Montreal, London, and other cities.
- \* Worked extensively with product management to analyze customer requirements and make product and implementation recommendations.

Informix Corp.

Software Development Lead

January 1994 - January 1997 (3 years 1 month)

Informix Corporation was one of the top RDBMS companies - it is now part of IBM.

- \* One of the key leads, helped grow the office from 15 to 150 people.
- \* One of 12 engineers who re-designed the Informix DBMS, transitioning it from PC/entry-level DBMS to one used by large corporations like Walmart. Informix revenues increased from hundred million US dollars to a billion US dollars.
- \* Architect of the SQL query optimizer filed two patents in this area.
- \* Lead teams of engineers to design, develop, and test the high-end, massively parallel Database engine.
- \* Worked with various customers to devise migration strategies for their system in order to best leverage this new architecture. This involved discussions on the choice of hardware, as well as a strategy to harness the features of the new DBMS.
- \* Wrote papers for various industry and academic publications and gave talks at International conferences.

Sequent Computer Inc.

Software Engineer

September 1991 - January 1994 (2 years 5 months)

Sequent Computers was a leading parallel computers company. Its multi-CPU machines were used by large corporations to run their Database Management Systems (DBMS). It has since been acquired by IBM.

Worked on the joint development project with Informix Software Inc. towards making the Informix DBMS work on Sequent's parallel computers. This involved re-architecting of the Informix DBMS. This project was very successful. Customers included Walmart, Fidelity, and EDS.

Education

## University of Oregon

MBA, Business Administration · (September 2004 - June 2006)

## University of Wisconsin, Madison

MS, Computer Science · (August 1989 - June 1991)

## **Cornell University**

BS, Computer Science and Mathematics · (August 1985 - June 1989)

International School Bangkok